<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="37"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[APRIL 2025 VOL. 1













             PMSMNU









            P R O G R A M   O F   M E D I C I N E   A N D   S U R G E R Y   M A N S O U R A   N A T I O N A L   U N I V E R S I T Y

                     MAGAZINE]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS







                    Introduction                                                                     3 - 5








                    Workshops and Seminars                                                          6 - 11







                    Awareness Campaign                                                            12 - 22









                    Community Services                                                            23 - 26










                    Educational Activities                                                         27 - 33







                    Exploring The Latest Updates                                                  34 - 35










                    Editorial Board & Social Media                                                 36 - 37]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Dear all,





                       It is with great pleasure to launch the first

                     volume of the Faculty of Medicine  Magazine.




                     This publication represents a new chapter in

                   how we celebrate, communicate, and reflect on

                         the many achievements, challenges, and


                    ongoing efforts within the faculty of medicine





                 Within the pages, we will find a vibrant showcase

                    of academic activities , educational initiatives,

                                         student achievements.




                   This magazine is more than a publication; it is a

                       platform for sharing ideas, for recognizing

                    excellence, and for strengthening the sense of

                       community that is essential to our mission




                     We invite all to read, to contribute, and most


                       of all, to engage with the ideas, the stories,

                                          and with one another






                                   Thank you,

           and welcome to the first volume of The

                  Faculty of Medicine Magazine.













                                                                                                                   3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[It  is  my  pleasure  to  announce  the  launch  of  the  first  volume  of  the
                 Medicine  Newsletter  at  Mansoura  National  University,  created  to  share
                 with you the faculty news, achievements, and student contributions during
                 the school year.


                 With  each  issue,  we  aim  to  showcase  the  academic  activities,  student
                 activities,  and  healthcare  initiatives  being  led  by  our  dedicated  medical
                 students.


                 This first issue features variety of news, including updates on innovative
                 medical research, accomplishments of our faculty and students, and news
                 about upcoming events and initiatives.


                 I encourage you to go through this issue and share it with your  peers.


                 By doing so, you help raise the awareness of the impactful work being done
                 by  the  faculty  of  medicine  and  students,  in  support  of  our  mission  to

                 achieve excellence in medical education, research, and healthcare service.


                  I look forward to celebrating many more accomplishments together in the
                 future.









                                    Prof: Cherif Khater


                                        President of Mansoura University

                                        and Mansoura National University











                                                                                                                   4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Welcome to the Faculty of Medicine: A Journey of Knowledge,
                                          Excellence, and Global Impact


                Joining  the  faculty  of  medicine  is  not  merely  an  academic  degree  but  a
                profound  commitment  to  the  well-being  of  humanity.  As  you  start  this
                transformative  journey  at  the  Program  of  Medicine-  Mansoura  National
                University,  you  are  entering  a  world  where  knowledge  meets  compassion,
                and where dedication paves the way for excellence.

                Medicine  is  a  subject  that  demands  resilience,  intellectual  curiosity,  and
                ethical  integrity.  The  challenges  you  will  encounter  will  shape  you  into  a
                physician  who  not  only  has  clinical  expertise  but  also  understands  the
                responsibility that comes with saving lives. Your learning here will equip you
                with the skills and competencies to diagnose, treat, and innovate, ensuring
                that you stand at the forefront of medical advancements both nationally and
                internationally.


                In  an  era  of  rapid  scientific  progress,  medical  professionals  must  be
                prepared  to  compete  and  collaborate  on  a  global  scale.  Our  curriculum  is
                designed  to  establish  a  strong  foundation  in  basic  medical  sciences  and
                clinical  practice,  foster  critical  thinking,  and  cultivate  leadership  qualities
                that  will  enable  you  to  navigate  the  complexities  of  modern  healthcare
                systems.  Research,  continuous  life-long  learning,  and  interdisciplinary
                collaboration will be fundamental to your growth as a physician.








                                    Prof: Amira Taman


                                    Director of the program of medicine and

                                     surgery, Mansoura National University











                                                                                                                   5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[WORKSHOPS







                               & SEMINARS]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Basic Medical skills workshops



      Starting from day one, our program is dedicated to enhancing essential medical

      skills,    including       patient      history-taking,       physical      exams,       and      effective
      communication.  We  prioritize  hands-on  learning,  ensuring  that  students  build
      confidence  and  competence  in  core  clinical  techniques.  This  early  focus  on

      foundational  skills  prepares  students  to  provide  safe,  high-quality  patient  care
      throughout their medical journey.



                     Injection and Cannulation Technique














































                         Blood Pressure and Blood grouping



























                                                                                                                   7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Antibiotic Sensitivity Testing


































                                               Antibiotic  Sensitivity  Test  (AST)  is  a  laboratory  test

                                               used  to  determine  which  antibiotics  are  effective
                                               against  a  specific  bacterial  infection.  It  helps  identify


                                               whether       bacteria      are     sensitive,      resistant,     or
                                               intermediate to certain antibiotics.


                                               Purpose of the Test:

                                                • Helps doctors choose the most effective antibiotic.

                                                • Prevents the misuse of antibiotics.

                                                • Reduces the risk of antibiotic resistance.


































                                                                                                                   8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[First Aid Workshop




















        Program of medicine and surgery organized the first workshop about “First Aid” presented by:
                       Dr/ Sahar wasel - at the General Administration of Medical Affairs.

         First aid is the initial help given to someone who is injured or ill. It includes basic treatments
                      like cleaning wounds, performing CPR, or applying bandages. Quick

   CPR technique:

   CPR (Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation) is a life-saving

   technique used when someone's heart or breathing stops. It
   involves chest compressions to maintain blood flow and, if

   needed, rescue breaths to supply oxygen. Quick action is vital,
   as it greatly improves survival chances until medical help

   arrives. Learning CPR is an essential skill for emergencies.
   What should you do in emergency situations?




   In an emergency, stay calm and focused. First, call for help.
   Quickly assess the situation and ensure it's safe for you to
   act. If needed, provide first aid, like CPR, or stop bleeding
   with pressure. Only move injured people if they’re in

   immediate danger. Stay with the person, reassure them,
   and wait for professionals to arrive, following their

   instructions carefully.









                                                                                                                 8
                                                                                                                   9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Workshop entitled


     "Quality of Academic and work Life: Skills



       and Strategies for Achieving Excellence"





   The  Faculty  of  Medicine  organized  a  workshop  entitled
   “Quality  of  Academic  and  work  Life:  Skills  and
   Strategies  for  Achieving  Excellence”,  during  which  Ms.
   Rita  Boulos,  Institutional  Training  Consultant  at  the
   National  Council  for  Training  and  Education,  addressed
   several important topics that aimed to enable students to
   face  the  challenges  of  academic  and  work  life,  defining
   the  concept  of  quality  of  academic  and  work  life,

   developing      effective    communication        skills   and
   interviewing  techniques,  the  stage  of  continuous
   improvement,  including  dealing  with  stress  and  solving
   problems  effectively,  and  basic  strategies  for  achieving
   excellence and creativity.



































                                                                                                                 3
                                                                                                                  10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Molecular genetics





    Spectrophotometry




    DNA extraction




























   Spectrophotography  and  DNA  extraction  are  essential  laboratory

   techniques used in molecular biology, genetics, and various research

   fields. Workshops focused on these methods provide critical hands-on

   experience for students, researchers, and professionals, making them

   vital for enhancing practical skills and advancing scientific knowledge.





                                 Spectrophotography  measures  the  intensity  of  light  absorbed  or

                                 transmitted  by  a  sample,  providing  valuable  data  about  its

                                 concentration and composition. In molecular biology, it is commonly

                                 used to quantify DNA, RNA, and protein concentrations.








   DNA extraction: is the process of isolating DNA from cells or tissues

   for analysis. This fundamental technique is used in various applications

   such as genetic testing, cloning, and forensic analysis.





                                                                                                                  11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[AWARENESS







                                CAMPAIGNS]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Hand hygiene





      Starting from day one, our program is dedicated to enhancing essential medical

      skills,    including      patient      history-taking,        physical      exams,       and     effective
      communication.  We  prioritize  hands-on  learning,  ensuring  that  students  build

      confidence  and  competence  in  core  clinical  techniques.  This  early  focus  on
      foundational  skills  prepares  students  to  provide  safe,  high-quality  patient  care
      throughout their medical journey.































       Prevention of Infections: Hand hygiene is one of the simplest,
       most effective ways to prevent the spread of infections, particularly
       in healthcare settings. A hand hygiene awareness campaign
       educates individuals on the importance of regular handwashing or
       using hand sanitizers to reduce the transmission of harmful

       pathogens like bacteria, viruses, and fungi.







                                           Improving Patient Safety: In healthcare, proper hand hygiene
                                           is critical in preventing hospital-acquired infections (HAIs), which

                                           can lead to prolonged illnesses, complications, or even death. A
                                           campaign helps healthcare professionals, patients, and visitors
                                           understand how proper hand hygiene can improve patient
                                           safety by preventing cross-contamination.





   Raising Public Awareness: Hand hygiene campaigns also target the
   general public, emphasizing the importance of handwashing in
   everyday life. Whether at home, work, or public spaces, understanding
   when and how to wash hands properly can significantly reduce the
   spread of contagious diseases like the flu, colds, and COVID-19.
                                                                                                                  13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[World Pneumonia Day







    World  Pneumonia  Day  is  observed  every  year  on

    November  12th  to  raise  global  awareness  about
    pneumonia,  its  causes,  prevention,  and  treatment.

    Pneumonia  is  a  leading  cause  of  death  worldwide,
    particularly in young children, the elderly, and those with

    weakened immune systems.

   The day serves to highlight the importance of collective action to reduce the global
  burden of pneumonia and prevent unnecessary deaths.


                                                Global Health Burden:



                                                   Pneumonia is one of the top causes of death, responsible

                                                   for  around  2.5  million  deaths  each  year  globally,

                                                   according to the World Health Organization (WHO).
                                                   It is especially deadly for children under the age of five,
                                                   accounting for 15% of all child deaths globally.



  How to protect yourself from pneumonia?



    Protecting  yourself  from  pneumonia  involves  a  combination  of  preventive  measures,  including

    vaccination, good hygiene, maintaining a healthy lifestyle, and managing chronic conditions. By staying
    proactive and taking care of your respiratory health, you can significantly reduce your risk of pneumonia

    and other respiratory infections. Always consult with your healthcare provider for personalized advice
    on how to protect yourself based on your age, health status, and risk factors.


















                                                                                                                  14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Stop Smoking and vaping



      Quitting smoking and vaping is one of the most important steps you can take for your

      health. Despite the challenges, the benefits such as reduced risks of cancer, heart disease,
      and improved lung functionare immense and long-lasting. With the right support,
      strategies, and determination, it's possible to break free from addiction and lead a
      healthier, more fulfilling life. The sooner you quit, the sooner your body begins to heal,
      improving both your physical and mental well-being.
































                             The Medicine and Surgery Program held an awareness

                               week against the harms of smoking and electronic
                                cigarettes. The celebration included an awareness
                                lecture in which Dr. Ahmed ElSukary - Lecturer of
                                Forensic Medicine and Toxicology at the Faculty of
                               Medicine - Mansoura University, lectured about the
                            harms of smoking and introducing passive smoking and
                             its harms, as well as the harms of electronic cigarettes.
































                                                                                                                  15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Tuberculosis












































           As part of the Faculty of Medicine’s keenness to spread health awareness
           among the students of Mansoura National University and to celebrate World
           Tuberculosis Day, the college held a tuberculosis awareness campaign where

           the students explained how the disease is transmitted and methods of
           prevention and treatment, especially since tuberculosis began to appear again
           with strains resistant to antibiotics, which represents a greater challenge in
           treating tuberculosis cases. Awareness also included distributing brochures to

           introduce tuberculosis and methods of diagnosis, prevention and treatment.



































                                                                                                                  16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[MonkeyPox



   A Monkeypox Awareness Campaign aims to educate the public about the symptoms, transmission,
   prevention, and treatment of the disease to help reduce the spread and ensure early detection. Below is
   a comprehensive framework for such a campaign.
























   What is Monkeypox?


       A viral zoonotic disease caused by the monkeypox virus,

       with symptoms similar to smallpox but milder.

       The disease is typically spread through contact with


       infected animals, people, or contaminated materials.

   . Causes: Monkeypoxcan result from:

     1.Animal-to-Human Transmission
     2.Human-to-Human Transmission
     3.Transmission via Contaminated Surfaces
     4.Close Contact and Respiratory Droplets

     5.Bites or Scratches from Infected Animals


                                    Prevention: Focusing on hand hygiene as a primary prevention
                                    measure against Monkeypox is a powerful and actionable strategy.
                                    Regular handwashing can significantly reduce the risk of transmission,
                                    as the virus is spread through contact with contaminated surfaces and

                                    bodily fluids. By raising awareness and encouraging people to wash
                                    their hands frequently, we empower communities to take control of
                                    their health and prevent the spread of the disease..
















                                                                                                                  17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[ADHD





      ADHD (Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder) is a complex

      neurodevelopmental disorder that affects both children and adults.
      While its exact cause is still not fully understood, it is believed to be

      influenced by a combination of genetic, environmental, and
      neurobiological factors. The symptoms, which include inattention,

      hyperactivity, and impulsivity, can significantly impact academic
      performance, work productivity, and personal relationships.










































      However, with proper diagnosis and treatment ranging from medication and behavioral therapy

      to lifestyle adjustments individuals with ADHD can manage their symptoms effectively and lead

      fulfilling lives. Early intervention, understanding, and support from family, friends, and
      educators play a crucial role in helping those with ADHD thrive.




                                       Increasing awareness and reducing stigma are

                                       essential to ensure that people with ADHD receive the

                                       support they need. By fostering an environment of
                                       acceptance and understanding, society can help

                                       individuals with ADHD reach their full potential



                                                                                                                  18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Mental Health






     Mental health: is a crucial aspect of overall well-being, encompassing emotional, psychological,
     and social health. It affects how individuals think, feel, and behave, as well as how they handle
     stress, relate to others, and make decisions. Mental health issues like depression and anxiety
     can significantly impact quality of life if not addressed properly. It's important to openly discuss

     mental health to reduce stigma and encourage people to seek support when needed. Taking
     care of mental health involves rest, healthy social interactions, and coping with stress in
     constructive ways.



























       How to enhance mental health?


        Exercise Regularly: Physical activity boosts mood and reduces stress.
        Get Enough Sleep: Proper rest improves emotional balance and cognitive function.

        Eat Well: A balanced diet supports both body and mind.
        Practice Mindfulness: Meditation and relaxation techniques reduce anxiety and
        enhance focus.
        Seek Support: Building strong social connections and seeking professional help
        when needed can significantly improve mental well-being.

                                                  Avoid Stigma

    Stigma often arises from misunderstandings or negative stereotypes, which can prevent people from
    seeking help or discussing their struggles openly. To combat stigma, it's important to promote awareness
    and education, emphasizing that mental health issues are just as valid as physical health concerns.
    Encouraging open conversations, showing empathy, and offering support can help reduce the stigma. By
    fostering an environment where people feel safe and understood, we can break down barriers and
    encourage more individuals to seek the help they need without fear of judgment.














                                                                                                                  19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Female Hysteria



   A Female Hysteria Awareness Campaign aims to educate the public about the symptoms, as well as the
   potential complications of delayed diagnosis and treatment, in addition to the importance of early
   detection and effective treatment methods.



























   What is Female Hysteria?

   Female hysteria was once a common medical diagnosis


   for  women.  It  includes  many  symptoms,  like  anxiety,

   shortness of breath, fainting, nervousness, , insomnia,

   fluid  retention,  heaviness  in  the  abdomen,  irritability,

   loss  of  appetite  for  food  or  sex,  and  a  "tendency  to


   cause trouble for others”.



   If someone is experiencing female hysteria, modern treatment options include:


       Therapy: Psychotherapy can help address underlying issues.

       Medical Treatment: If necessary, medications may be prescribed by a doctor.

       Lifestyle Changes: Regular exercise, stress management techniques.
























                                                                                                                  20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Excessive use of Antibiotics
































   Overusing antibiotics can lead to serious problems, including:


        Antibiotic Resistance:  Bacteria become resistant, making

        infections harder to treat.

        Loss of Good Bacteria: Disrupts gut bacteria.

        Side Effects: Can cause nausea, diarrhea, or allergic reactions.


        Weakened Immunity: weakening the immune system.

        Higher Costs: Resistant infections require stronger, more

        expensive treatments.

   To avoid these risks, use antibiotics only when prescribed and


   follow medical advice.
































                                                                                                                  21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[HIV/AIDS





     AIDS symptoms include a group of signs that appear when the immune system deteriorates due

     to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). These symptoms include:

     Fever,  Fatigue,  Weight  loss,  Frequent  infections,  Night  sweats,  Swollen  lymph  nodes,  Rashes,
     Diarrhea, Cough, shortness of breath and Memory loss.



     These symptoms usually appear in the advanced stages of AIDS. Early diagnosis and treatment

     are important to limit the progression of the disease.



























     If you think you might be infected with HIV:

      1. Stay calm and don’t panic.
      2. Visit a doctor for an HIV test.

      3. If the result is positive, start antiretroviral treatment (ART) as soon as possible.
      4. Avoid transmitting the virus to others by using condoms and not sharing needles.

      5. Follow up with your doctor regularly to maintain your health.



     Early treatment helps control the virus and allows you to live a healthy life.

























                                                                                                                  22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[COMMUNITY







                                       SERVICES]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[The Program received a visit from



        Al-Wadi Official Language School for Girls







































   The Program received a visit from Al-Wadi Public Language School for

   Girls, and they were received by a number of Professor Dr. Amira

   Taman - Director of the Medicine and Surgery Program and a number

   of faculty members, including Prof. Dr. Wael Al-Saeed - Professor of
   Anatomy and Dr. Dalia Mahfouz - lecturer Histology



























                                                                                                                  24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Visit the persons with disabilities


                                   Services Center










































     The visit comes within the framework of getting to know the educational, psychological, social
     and cultural services provided by the center to students with various disabilities, as well as the
     facilities  provided  for  each  disability  and  the  training  provided  by  the  center  for  students  in
     Braille and the principles of sign language. Explaining the meaning of the term "disabled", how
     to  integrate  people  with  disabilities  into  society  and  how  society  deals  with  them,  how  to
     challenge  and  have  the  will  to  achieve  success  for  them,  the  preference  for  using  the  term
     "differently capable" and what are the principles of the Convention on the Rights of Persons
     with  Disabilities,  with  a  simplified  explanation  of  the  Law  on  the  Rights  of  Persons  with

     Disabilities, and awareness of the issues of persons with disabilities.
































                                                                                                                  25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Visit to Mansoura college schools

















































     The  Faculty  of  Medicine  organized  a  four-day
     visit to Mansoura College schools in Mansoura
     for  its  various  stages  (kindergarten,  primary,

     preparatory,      secondary),      which     included
     awareness  campaigns  on  various  topics,
     including first aid, healthy nutrition, awareness
     against  bullying  and  how  to  confront  it,  and
     breast cancer.
































                                                                                                                  26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[EDUCATIONAL







                                    ACTIVITIES]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University
                                             Anatomy Museum




















      Within the framework of supporting the bonds of cooperation between Mansoura University
      and Mansoura National University, students from the Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura National
      University, visited the Anatomy Museum at the Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, in
      the presence of Prof. Dr. Amira Taman, Program Director, and the faculty members of the
      Anatomy and Medical Embryology course.



















      An anatomy museum plays a vital role in medical education, offering students and healthcare
      professionals a deeper understanding of the human body. Its importance includes:

      Hands-On Learning:
       Anatomy museums provide access to preserved human specimens, allowing students to study
      the body’s structure up close. This hands-on experience reinforces textbook knowledge,
      enhancing learning and retention.

      Visual Reference:
       The museum offers detailed models, cadavers, and anatomical displays that help students

      visualize complex structures, making it easier to understand spatial relationships between organs,
      muscles, and tissues.
      Clinical Application:
       Understanding human anatomy is essential for accurate diagnosis, surgery, and patient care. The

      museum's resources help bridge the gap between theoretical knowledge and clinical practice by
      providing real-world examples of anatomy in health and disease.















                                                                                                                  28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[The first scientific day of the Faculty of


            Medicine - Mansoura National University




  Believing in the directives of the Egyptian state to support youth and the fact that the university is the
  nucleus of fourth-generation universities that adopt different frameworks in education, and keenness to
  spread the culture of scientific research, creativity, innovation and investing in students’ capabilities, a
  number of different topics were discussed during the day and students presented their research for
  evaluation by a specialized committee of professors. From today, it is the nucleus of student scientific
  activity adopted by the college and the university with the aim of discovering students’ talents, abilities
  and creative research tendencies and developing them.










































































                                                                                                                  29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Faculty of medicine - Tanta university



                      Annual conference - 2024



































































                                                                                                                  30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Faculty of medicine - Mansoura university



  Anatomic Pathology conference - 2024



































































                                                                                                                  31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Annual Conference of the Department of



               Medical Parasitology, Faculty of



                Medicine, Mansoura University





























   As part of encouraging students to engage in scientific research and providing a
   stimulating research environment, the students of the Faculty of Medicine,
   Mansoura National University participated in organizing and attending the
   International Conference of the Department of Medical Parasitology at the
   Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University. The conference activities included
   three scientific sessions, featuring 15 presentations delivered by faculty members
   from various disciplines, universities, and research institutes within Egypt.
    Additionally, 4 presentations were given by faculty members from abroad, including the United States, Saudi
   Arabia, and Ethiopia. Furthermore, 3 scientific posters were presented during the conference.







































                                                                                                                  32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[A two-day workshop at the Faculty of Medicine to

    enhance students’ skills and train them on various



                                     assessment methods






































   The  workshop  included  a  lecture  titled

   “How  to  Design  an  Infographic”  given
   by  Dr.  Dalia  Mahfouz,  the  third  semester
   coordinator,  in  which  she  discussed  the

   scientific  and  technical  foundations  of
   designing  infographics  as  an  innovative

   means  of  presenting  information  in  an
   attractive and easy way.










                                                             It  also  included  a  lecture  entitled
                                                             “Extended  Matching  Questions  (EMQ)”

                                                             presented by Professor Dr. Amira Taman,
                                                             during  which  she  focused  on  introducing

                                                             students to EMQ questions as one of the

                                                             modern          assessment           tools,       which
                                                             contribute to developing students’ critical

                                                             thinking and analysis skills.



                                                                                                                  33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[EXPLORING










                      LATEST UPDATES]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Exploring the acute and chronic effects of a multistrain

                probiotic supplement on cognitive function and mood in
                    healthy older adults: a randomized controlled trial


              The study investigates the effects of a multistrain probiotic supplement on cognitive
                function and mood in healthy older adults through a randomized controlled trial.




        Cognitive Decline and Aging

             Cognitive decline is a prevalent aspect of aging,
           affecting memory, learning, and executive functions,

         particularly in the hippocampus and prefrontal cortex.
           This decline is often accompanied by mental health

              issues, such as geriatric depression, which can

                     exacerbate cognitive deterioration.

   Gut Microbiota Changes with Aging

           Aging is associated with significant alterations in gut

         microbiota, characterized by reduced diversity and shifts
        in microbial taxa, which may impact cognitive and mental

         health through the gut-brain axis.  Dysbiosis can lead to

          increased inflammation and compromised gut barrier

          integrity, potentially contributing to cognitive decline.

   Probiotic Interventions for Cognitive Health


                     Probiotic supplementation has emerged as a potential strategy to mitigate
                      cognitive decline and improve mood in older adults, although evidence in

                  healthy populations remains limited.  The study hypothesizes that probiotics will

                 enhance working memory and executive function while reducing negative mood.



                         Conclusions of the study and Future Directions


       The findings suggest that chronic multispecies probiotic

        supplementation may enhance executive function and
         reduce cognitive biases in healthy older adults, with

      potential clinical applications for depression prevention.
       Future research should explore the mechanisms behind
      these effects and consider additional factors influencing

                               gut microbiota.






                                                                                                                  35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[EDITORIAL BOARD







                             & SOCIAL MEDIA]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[MEET THE EDITORIAL BOARD






















                                            Prof/ Amira Taman






















     Hamdy Ahmed                    Ahmed Taha                 Shahd Ezat              Afnan Hany






















                 Hany Kamal                    Reda khalifa               Mohamed Abo Elmagd







            SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORMS













                                                                                                                  37]]></page></pages></Search>